<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cloud Security on My Personal Blog</title><link>/tags/cloud-security/</link><description>Recent content in Cloud Security on My Personal Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 11:35:07 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/cloud-security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Securing the Cloud: A Detailed Guide to Vulnerability Management in Cloud Environments</title><link>/posts/vm_cloud/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 11:35:07 +0530</pubDate><guid>/posts/vm_cloud/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As cloud computing becomes vital to modern business operations, managing vulnerabilities within cloud environments is paramount for cybersecurity professionals. Understanding the diverse cloud deployment models, shared security responsibilities, common risks, and best practices ensures a comprehensive defense against emerging threats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="cloud-environments-overview"&gt;Cloud Environments Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cloud environments can be broadly categorized into three types — &lt;strong&gt;public&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;private&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;hybrid&lt;/strong&gt; clouds — each offering unique advantages and security considerations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Public Cloud:&lt;/strong&gt; Resources are hosted on infrastructure owned by a third-party provider (e.g., AWS, Azure, Google Cloud) and shared among multiple tenants. The scale and flexibility are unmatched, but it requires strict attention to configuration and access controls due to multi-tenancy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Private Cloud:&lt;/strong&gt; The cloud infrastructure is dedicated exclusively to one organization, either hosted on-premises or by a third party. This model offers greater control and customization but requires more internal security management.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hybrid Cloud:&lt;/strong&gt; This approach combines public and private cloud elements, allowing data and applications to move between environments. Hybrid clouds demand sophisticated integration and security strategies to protect data crossing these boundaries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each environment&amp;rsquo;s architecture affects how vulnerabilities manifest and must be managed, shaping the risk profile and remediation tactics.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>