<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CyberSecurity on My Personal Blog</title><link>/tags/cybersecurity/</link><description>Recent content in CyberSecurity on My Personal Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 14:02:21 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/cybersecurity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What is the OSI Model? A Simple Guide for IT and Cybersecurity Pros 🌐📶</title><link>/posts/osimodel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 14:02:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>/posts/osimodel/</guid><description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id="tags-osi-model-networking-cybersecurity-it-basics-network-layers-protocols"&gt;title: &amp;ldquo;What is the OSI Model? A Simple Guide for IT and Cybersecurity Pros&amp;rdquo;
meta-description: &amp;ldquo;Learn what the OSI model is, how it works, and why it matters in networking and cybersecurity. A clear, step-by-step breakdown of all 7 OSI layers.&amp;rdquo;
keywords: &amp;ldquo;OSI model, networking layers, 7 layers of OSI, OSI explained, OSI model tutorial, network communication model, cybersecurity OSI&amp;rdquo;
tags: [&amp;ldquo;OSI Model&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Networking&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Cybersecurity&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;IT Basics&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Network Layers&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Protocols&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding the &lt;strong&gt;OSI (Open Systems Interconnection)&lt;/strong&gt; model is foundational for anyone in networking, IT, or cybersecurity. It breaks down how data moves from one device to another in a network — layer by layer. This conceptual model helps troubleshoot network issues, design secure systems, and understand communication protocols.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title> EDR vs AV vs MDR: How to Choose the Right Cybersecurity Solution 🛡️💻</title><link>/posts/edr-av-mdr/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 10:39:12 +0530</pubDate><guid>/posts/edr-av-mdr/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In today&amp;rsquo;s digital world, ensuring the security of your devices and data is more crucial than ever. Cybersecurity solutions like &lt;strong&gt;EDR&lt;/strong&gt; (Endpoint Detection and Response), &lt;strong&gt;AV&lt;/strong&gt; (Antivirus), and &lt;strong&gt;MDR&lt;/strong&gt; (Managed Detection and Response) each offer different approaches to protecting your organization from cyber threats. But which one is right for you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This step-by-step guide will break down the key differences between these three solutions, so you can choose the best option for your needs. 🔍&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Types of Cybersecurity Threats</title><link>/posts/typesofthreats/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/typesofthreats/</guid><description>&lt;p align="justify"&gt;Cybersecurity threats come in many shapes and sizes. Some of the most common threats include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Malware:&lt;/strong&gt; Malicious software designed to damage or gain unauthorized access to computers or networks. Types of malware include viruses, worms, ransomware, and spyware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phishing:&lt;/strong&gt; Cybercriminals trick individuals into revealing sensitive information, such as login credentials or financial details, by pretending to be legitimate entities via email, phone, or social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ransomware:&lt;/strong&gt; A form of malware that encrypts the victim&amp;rsquo;s files, demanding a ransom for their release. It has become one of the most financially devastating attacks in recent years.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cybersecurity Roles</title><link>/posts/securityroles/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 16:23:07 +0530</pubDate><guid>/posts/securityroles/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity is a dynamic and complex field, encompassing a wide range of roles and responsibilities aimed at safeguarding an organization’s information, networks, and systems. These roles are critical in defending against the growing and evolving landscape of cyber threats. From strategic decision-making to hands-on technical tasks, various cybersecurity professionals work together to build comprehensive security measures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the most common cybersecurity roles found in organizations today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chief Information Security Officer (CISO)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Introduction - Cybersecurity</title><link>/posts/cybersecurity/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 16:15:03 +0530</pubDate><guid>/posts/cybersecurity/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In today&amp;rsquo;s hyper-connected world, cybersecurity has become more crucial than ever. With the rapid advancement of technology and the increasing frequency of cyberattacks, safeguarding sensitive information is paramount. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re an individual, a business, or a large organization, understanding the importance of cybersecurity is the first step toward creating a secure digital environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Cybersecurity?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity refers to the practice of protecting systems, networks, devices, and data from malicious attacks, damage, or unauthorized access. As the digital landscape evolves, so do the methods cybercriminals use to exploit vulnerabilities. Cybersecurity encompasses a wide range of measures, including technology, processes, and practices, all designed to ensure the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of information.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>